<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>EBB Ssouvke</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on EBB Ssouvke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 09:23:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ebbssouvke.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/27494938-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 09:23:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/27494938-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>In Matthew 25, Jesus mentions several important groups that are particularly vulnerable in the world: "the least of these my brethren," including strangers, sick people, prisoners, "the naked," as well as widows and orphans (25:31-46). Jesus specifically says, “I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me … Truly I say to you … to the extent that you did it to one of these brothers of Mine, you did it to Me” (25:35-40).</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/82289204-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:11:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/82289204-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>It has been said that our deepest fear is not that we are inadequate. Our deepest fear is that we are powerful beyond measure because we are all connected to God. This fear of tapping into the innate power we possess limits us from receiving the blessings God has for us. Sometimes life throws us curve balls that seem to dismantle our worlds, and at these times, maintaining confidence in God can feel challenging.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/27334160-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/27334160-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>Building upon a strong foundation ensures stability and endurance through both good times and bad. In the construction industry, this means selecting quality materials and ensuring they are properly installed. Similarly, in the spiritual realm, individuals need a solid foundation for their lives, which must be based on unwavering truth. As Christians, evaluating what our livesare built on is crucial since we seek to grow in faith and deepen our relationship with God.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/16727543-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/16727543-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>The beliefs related to Hell are sometimes seen as extreme or unnecessarily dark in nature among some Christians. This view suggests that Christians prefer dwelling on the idea of people going to Hell instead of focusing on spiritual growth and the love of God. However, both perspectives are crucial aspects of Christian faith. In this article, we'll explore why Christians emphasize Hell and balance this concept with the possibility of not being with God in Heaven.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/70059799-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 15:14:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/70059799-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>"Be kind, for everyone you meet is fighting a hard battle." This famous quote by Plato reflects a simple yet profound truth. We don't know the struggles people may be facing in their lives. As humans, we're all vulnerable to feelings of hopelessness, loneliness, disappointment, fear, anxiety, and more. Kindness can bring a moment of relief, even joy to those facing a difficult life situation.
You might think that Christians have an advantage when it comes to being kind.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/51803104-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 06:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/51803104-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>Christian Fundamentalism is one of the significant religious movements that began at the turn of the twentieth century. It emerged in response to modernist views that were challenging traditional doctrines like biblical inerrancy.
While it shares much in common with traditional orthodox Christianity, it has its distinct characteristics and controversial elements. This article explores the good and bad aspects of Christian Fundamentalism to provide a balanced perspective.
The Good Aspects 1.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/93271399-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 18:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/93271399-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>As a church leader, you want your congregation to view you as a pillar of strength—someone who can handle anything that life throws your way. While many pastors do possess impressive resilience, even the strongest leaders are human. This means pastors can experience struggles just like anyone else. One major roadblock for many church leaders is learning how to ask for help.
Asking for assistance is an integral part of personal growth and development, but it can feel unnatural to those accustomed to a leadership role where independence and strength are valued.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/54886252-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:08:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/54886252-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>When a church is struggling with some area(s) of leadership and decision making, they often look for outside assistance. This is a wise move. It is helpful to have an objective third party to come in and provide perspective on the unique challenges each ministry is facing. With the right approach and attitude, church consultants can greatly assist in identifying the root causes of problems and leading church leaders to formulate workable solutions.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/52991998-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:54:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/52991998-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>Guilt is a common human experience often characterized by feelings of remorse or sorrow for one's own wrongdoing. This emotion typically prompts inner reflection and external attempts at recompense. In Christian belief, guilt refers specifically to "missing the mark" of God’s holy standard of morality as laid out in His Word. As a result, guilt should never be seen as a positive experience in the Christian life, but rather as a prompting toward repentance, self-examination, confession, and restoration.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/44661153-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 22:17:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/44661153-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>The topic of heaven often brings up many diverging perspectives, which can be confusing to many individuals seeking truth. This confusion arises due to the influences of human speculation and cultural practices that contrast with Scriptural teachings. This article will explain the reasons why so many ideas about heaven are not biblical and provide biblical clarity on thee subject to promote spiritual understanding.
Reasons for Non-Biblical Ideas About Heaven Cultural Influence: Culture plays a significant role in shaping people's perception of afterlife realities.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/21018221-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 19:22:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/21018221-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>In order to understand what Jesus teaches us about God's end times plan, we must look closely at the teachings of Jesus Himself as well as consider how His followers throughout history have interpreted His teachings concerning the future.
The Teachings of Jesus Regarding the End Times Throughout His earthly ministry, Jesus frequently spoke about His return and the ultimate fate of humanity. However, when examining His teachings, it is important to remember that Jesus spoke in parables and in allegories, often using imagery and language that may seem cryptic or indirect to modern readers.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/64714586-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 23:41:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/64714586-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>Over the past few decades, we have witnessed a steady decline in religious affiliation in many Western societies. In the United States, church attendance has shrunk while "nones"—those identifying as religiously unaffiliated—continue to increase in number. The "nones" now constitute the second largest religious group in America at roughly 23% of the population. This trend is not unique to America; it has been observed in European countries like France, Italy, Spain, and Germany as well.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/80670500-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/80670500-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>I’ve been a Christian for decades now, and over those years I've learned a few things. My hope is that these lessons might help both new believers and older ones like me stay focused on what truly matters as we journey with Christ.
1. Keep it Simple It can be easy to get distracted by all the intricate doctrines and complicated dogmas of our faith. But Jesus kept His message simple, telling us to love God and love one another.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/93485425-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:18:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/93485425-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>A pastor friend recently shared her heartache over a congregant who felt he needed to apologize for prioritizing his own mental health. The question he struggled with, “Is self-care selfish?” This query often surfaces in the broader culture as well. Is seeking out the healthiest choices a responsibility or a vice, an expression of maturity or self-absorption? In many arenas, self-care can be as controversial as other forms of caring for the self, such as birth control and sexual exploration.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/57719080-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 21:38:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/57719080-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>The church can sometimes be an intimidating place where everyone seems to have it together except for you. Even though people inside the body of Christ are all believers in Christ, there can still be a lot of disagreements between individual believers. There is not necessarily a universal understanding of what the word family means or implies in this context. That's a significant challenge when we are trying to encourage one another to treat each other like family members.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/21128646-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:24:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/21128646-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>Technological advancements seem to be happening at an alarming rate of speed in this contemporary era. New innovations are continuously being introduced while older ones have already become an integral part of our day-to-day lives. This is an era of fast connectivity, artificial intelligence, bionic limbs, and self-driving cars. However, just as with every other aspect of life, there are appropriate and inappropriate ways to utilize technological progress. As followers of Christ, it is imperative that we critically evaluate any development in light of Scripture.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/19363076-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ebbssouvke.github.io/posts/19363076-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The history of Christianity has been marked by periods of persecution and tolerance interspersed with periods of prosperity or entente cordiale. Particularly in the Western world, Christianity has enjoyed many periods of social, cultural, and legal liberties since Constantine legalized the religion in 313 AD. These freedoms have allowed the church to exert significant influence over education, morality, governance, among other key aspects of society.
Despite its many blessings, Christianity does not exist in a vacuum.</description></item></channel></rss>